Finding Aid for the Rudolph H. Kampmeier Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Rudolph H. Kampmeier Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0235
.84 linear_feet
The materials in the Rudolph H. Kampmeier Collection are arranged in alphabetical order. Brackets were used when a location was not positively known.
- All the Way Home by Tad Mosel based on novel A Death In the Family by James Agee - Belasco Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
- The American College of Physicians Annual Banquet featuring Bob Hope - Biltmore Hotel, Los Angeles, April 19, 1956 (Box 1)
- Amphitryon 38, a comedy by Jean Giraudoux - Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, March 7, 1939 (Box 1)
- Annie Get Your Gun, Rodgers and Hammerstein production with music and lyrics by Irving Berlin, starring Billie Worth - Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, March 21 and 22, 1949 (Box 1)
- Auntie Mame, a new comedy by Jerome Lawrence and Robert E. Lee, based on the novel by Patrick Dennis, starring Sylvia Sidney - Tennessee Theatre, Nashville (Box 1)
- Babes in Arms by George Oppenheimer music by Richard Rogers and lyrics by Lorenz Hart - Theatre Nashville, Nashville, May 1961 (Box 1)
- Bad Seed starring Nancy Kelly Week of - Harris Theatre, Chicago, June 3, 1956 (Box 1)
- Ballets Espagnols, choreograped and directed by Teresa and Luisillo - Community Concert Association, New York City (Box 1)
- Born Yesterday by Garson Kanin - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville (Box 1)
- The Boy Friend, a new musical comedy of the 1920's by Sandy Wilson - Theatre Nashville, Nashville, April 17-25, 1959 (Box 1)
- Brigadoon, a musical play in 2 acts by Alan Jay Lerner - New Theatre Nashville, Nashville, April 13-April 23, 1960 (Box 1)
- Bus Stop by William Inge - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, February 21- March 2, 1957 (Box 1)
- Caine Mutiny Court Martial by Herman Wouk - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, February 23-March 3, 1956 (Box 1)
- Camelot starring Richard Burton and Julie Andrews, production staged by Moss Hart - Majestic Theatre, New York City, December 3, 1960 (Box 1)
- Camille by Alexandre Dumas Fils starring Carmen Mathews - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville (Box 1)
- Cat On A Hot Tin Roof, by Tennessee Williams - Circle Theatre, Nashville, November 5-15, 1958 (Box 1)
- The Cave Dwellers, William Saroyan - Theatre Nashville, Nashville, January 18-27, 1962 (Box 1)
- Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra presented by the comunity Concert Association - Nashville, February 26, 1952 (Box 1)
- The Columbus Pilgrimage to Ante Bellum Homes, co-sponsored by the Columbus Chamber of Commerce - Columbus, Mississippi, March 26-April 3, 1960 (Box 1)
- Don Cossack, the original chorus and dancers, directed by Serge Jaroff, Thursday January 15 - War Memorial Auditorium, Nashville (Box 1)
- The Curious - Savage by John Patrick starring Zasu Pitts - Theatre Nashville, Nashville, November 1960 (Box 1)
- Cyrano de Bergerac, the Brian Hooker version of Edmond Rostand's immortal play - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville (Box 1)
- Danced Theatre, presented by the Community Concert Association with Ruth Mata and Eugene Hari and company - Community Concert Association, New York City (Box 1)
- The Dark at the Top of the Stairs by William Inge - Theatre Nashville, Nashville, March 22-31,1962 (Box 1)
- Death of A Salesman, by Arthur Miller - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, April 9-18, 1953 (Box 1)
- Henri Deering, Pianist, presented by the Community Concert Association - [Nashville] (Box 1)
- Detective Story by Sidney Kingsley - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville (Box 1)
- Dial M for Murder by Frederick Knott - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, December 1-10, 1955 (Box 1)
- Fallen Angels, a comedy in 3 acts, by Noel Coward - New Theatre Nashville, Nashville (Box 1)
- Arthur Fiedler and the Boston Pops Orchestra presented by the Community Concert Association - [Nashville] (Box 1)
- Finian's Rainbow, a musical fantasy, book by E.Y. Harburg and Fred Saidy - Nashville Community Playhouse, [Nashville], June 11-23, 1950 (Box 1)
- Flower Drum Song, a Rodgers and Hammerstein production, starring Elaine Dunn - American Theatre, St. Louis, October 31-November 12, 1960 (Box 1)
- The Fourposter by Jan de Hartog - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, October 14-23, 1955 (Box 1)
- Gentlemen prefer Blondes by Anita Loos and Joseph Fields - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, May 19-29, 1954 (Box 1)
- The Glass Menagerie by Tennessee Williams - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, January 28-February 4, 1948 (Box 1)
- Goodbye My Fancy by Fay Kanin - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, March 28-April 7, 1951 (Box 1)
- The Great Waltz by Moss Hart - Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, November 19, 1936 (Box 1)
- Half a Sixpence by H.G. Wells' Kipps, starring Tommy Steele - Broadhurst Theatre, New York City, June 1965 (Box 1)
- Happy Birthday, a comedy in two acts, by Anita Loos - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, November 16-26, 1949 (Box 1)
- Hellz a Poppin, presented by Olsen and Johnson, starring Jay C. Flippen and Happy Felton - Winter Garden, New York City, October 5, 1941 (Box 1)
- Hello Dolly, starring Ginger Rogers - St. James Theatre, New York City, April 1966 (Box 1)
- Nicole Henriot, pianist, presented by the Community Concert Association - [Nashville] (Box 1)
- The Indoor Sport by Jack B. Perry - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, April 22-May 1, 1954 (Box 1)
- Inherit The Wind by Jerome Lawrence and Robert E. Lee (Box 1)
- ' starring Paul Muni - National Theatre, New York City, March 19, 1956 (Box 1)
- Ed Begley and Tony Randall' - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, January 10-18, 1958 (Box 1)
- Julius Caesar by William Shakespeare - Theatre Nashville, Nashville, January, 1961 (Box 1)
- Kind Lady by Edward Chodorov - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, February 27-March 8, 1952 (Box 1)
- King of Hearts by Jean Kerr and Eleanor Brooke - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, October 13-22, 1955 (Box 1)
- Lady Audley's Secret, directed by Laverne Seeman - The First Theatre, Pacific Grove, CA, February 9-March 30, 1968 (Box 1)
- Lady in the Dark by Moss Hart, starring Gertrude Lawrence - Alvin Theatre, New York City, October 13, 1941 (Box 1)
- Life with Father by Russel Crouse and Howard Lindsay - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, March 5-14, 1953 (Box 1)
- Lotte Lehmann, leading Soprano Metropolitan Opera Ass'n, presented by the Community Concert Association - [Nashville] (Box 1)
- Light Up The Sky by Moss Hart - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, May 21-30, 1953 (Box 1)
- Look Back In Anger by John Osborne - New Theatre Nashville, Nashville, March 16-26, 1960 (Box 1)
- Look Homeward, Angel by Ketti Frings - Theatre Nashville, Nashville, April, 1961 (Box 1)
- Luv by Murray Schisgal, starring Eli Wallach, Anne Jackson and Alan Arkin - Booth Theatre, New York City, June 1965 (Box 1)
- Macbeth by William Shakespeare - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, April 25- May 4, 1949 (Box 1)
- MAdame Butterfly, music by Giacomo Puccini - Theatre Nashville, Nashville (Box 1)
- The Madwoman of Chaillot by Jean Giraudoux - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, January 1-February 10, 1951 (Box 1)
- Man and Superman by George Bernard Shaw - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, December 6-16, 1950 (Box 1)
- The Master of Ballantrae by Robert Louis Stevenson, starring Walker Whiteside - Tulane Theatre, Louisiana, January 13, 1935 (Box 1)
- The Minneapolis Orchestra, conductor Antal Dorati - [Nashville] (Box 1)
- Mister Roberts by Thomas Heggen and Josh Logan - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, December 2-11, 1954 (Box 2)
- The Moon is Blue by F. Hugh Herbert, a delightfully sophisticated comedy of young love - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, December 3-12, 1953 (Box 2)
- Moulin Rouge, Frank Senne's - Hollywood, CA (Box 2)
- The Music Man, starring Forrest Tucker - Shubert theatre, Chicago, April 19, 1959 (Box 2)
- My Fair Lady, production staged by (Box 2)
- Moss Hart, adapted from Bernard Shaw's (Box 2)
- Pygmalion (Box 2)
- ' starring Michael Allinson and Margot Moser - Mark He1linger Theatre, Nashville, March 13, 1961 (Box 2)
- ' starring Michael Evans and Anne Rogers - Shubert Theatre, Chicago, October 5, 1958 (Box 2)
- My Sister Eileen, a new play by Joseph Fields and Jerome Chodorov, presented by Max Gordon - Biltmore Theatre, New York City, October 13, 1941 (Box 2)
- Nashville Symphony Orchestra, conductor Guy Taylor (Box 2)
- - War Memorial Auditorium, Nashville, February 22, 1955 (Box 2)
- December 11 - Vanderbilt Memorial Gymnasium, Nashville (Box 2)
- Night Must Fall by Emlyn Williams - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, April 19-22, 1939 (Box 2)
- Of Mice and Men by John Steinbeck - Nashville Community, Nashville, March 21-26, 1955 (Box 2)
- Oliver, book, music and lyrics by Lionel Bart starring Judy Bruce and Robin Ramsay, directed by Peter Coe - Shubert Theatre, Chicago, March 1965 (Box 2)
- On Borrowed Time by Paul Osborn - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, February 7'12, 1955 (Box 2)
- One Of The Family by Kenneth Webb - Bonstelle Playhouse, Detroit, February 7, 1927 (Box 2)
- The Oxford Players in a series of Romantic Masterpieces; The Ivory Door, Hamlet, and Romeo and Juliet - Tulane Theatre, Louisiana, December 24 (Box 2)
- The Pajama Game, book by George Abbott and Richard Bissell, music and lyrics by Richard Adler and Jerry Ross (Box 2)
- ' starring John Raitt, Janis Paige and Eddie Foy, Jr.; choreography by Bob Fosse - St. James Theatre, New York City, April 25, 1955 (Box 2)
- ' - The Circle Theatre, Nashville, March 29-April 7, 1962 (Box 2)
- Pal Joey starring Andy Williams and Julie Wilson; music by Richard Rodgers, lyrics by Lornz Hart - Columbus, Ohio (Box 2)
- Personal Appearance by Lawrence Riley starring Carole Arden - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, March 3-12, 1949 (Box 2)
- The Philadelphia Story by Philip Barry starring George Hamilton - Columbus, Ohio (Box 2)
- Passing Show of 1926 - Shubert-Detroit Opera Detroit House, October 24, 1926 (Box 2)
- The Play's The Thing, a classic modern comedy by Ferenc Molnar - Tulane Theatre, New Orleans, LA, December 25, 1932 (Box 2)
- Private Lives by Noel Coward, starring Donald Cook - Ryman Autitorium, Nashville, January 17, 1950 (Box 2)
- Pygmalion by George Bernard Shaw - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, January 25-February 4, 1950 (Box 2)
- Michael Rabin, violinist; presented by the Community Concert Association - [Nashville] (Box 2)
- Radio City Music Hall Program-week beginning Thursday, April 14, 1966; Music Hall Grand Organ RAce with the Wind Glory of Easter Hello Spring Ambassadors of Spring Flowers that Bloom in the Spring Dog Antics Happy Bunnies April in Paris - Radio City Music Hall, Nashville (Box 2)
- Radio City Music Hall Program cont Handiest Chap this Spring Spring in Eastertown - Radio City Music Hall, New York City (Box 2)
- The Singing Nun' starring Debbie Reynolds Ricardo Montalban, Greer Garson, Agnes Moorehead, and Chad Everett (Box 2)
- The Rainmaker by N. Richard Nash - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, January 12- 21, 1956 (Box 2)
- The Red Mill, a comic Operetta, by Victor Herbert - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, October 15-25, 1952 (Box 2)
- Roberta, a play with music in two acts, based on a story by Alice Duer Miller, music by Jerome Kern - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, May 31-June 10, 1950 (Box 2)
- Relative Strangers by Armand Salacrou - Theatre Nashville, Nashville, March 19-28, 1959 (Box 2)
- Romeo and Juliet, by William Shakespeare - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, April 26-May 6, 1950 (Box 2)
- The Royal Family or A Comedy of Actors, by George S. Kaufman and Edna Ferber - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, March 15-25, 1950 (Box 2)
- The Royal Hunt of the Sun, a new play by Peter Shaffer, starring Christopher Plummer, Da'id Carradine and George Rose - Anta Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
- The St. Louis Symphony Orchestra, conductor Vladimir Golschmann - Nashville, January 7, 1954 (Box 2)
- St. Louis Woman, book by Arna Bontemps and Countee Cullen - Nashville Community, Nashville, May 28-June 7, 1952 (Box 2)
- San Carlo Grand Opera Company, January 9-12 - Municipal Auditorium, Nashville (Box 2)
- San Francisco Ballet - War Memorial Opera House, Nashville, April 4, 1960 (Box 2)
- Say, Darling, a comedy about a musical by Richard Bissell, Abe Burrows, and Marian Bissell - New Theatre Nashville, Nashville, October 7-17, 1959 (Box 2)
- Second Decade of the Playhouse describing the theatre movement in Nashville, published - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, October 8, 1945 (Box 2)
- Seperated Tables by Terence Rattigan - Theatre Nashville, Nashville, December 5-13, 1958 (Box 2)
- The Seven Year Itch by George Axelrod - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, May 24'June 2, 1956 (Box 2)
- The Silver Whistle by robert E. McEnroe - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, January 16-26, 1952 (Box 2)
- The Spider, a mystery melodrama by Fulton Oursler and Lowell Brentano - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, October 5-15, 1949 (Box 2)
- The Sound of Music, music and lyrics by Rodgers and Hammerstein, starring Jeannie Carson and John van Dreelen - Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, April 29- May 1, 1963 (Box 2)
- South Pacific, music and lyrics by Rodgers and Hammerstein, starring Martha Wright and George Britton - Nashville (Box 2)
- Rise Stevens of the Metropolitan Opera Association,, presented by the Community Concert Association - [Nashville] (Box 2)
- The Student Prince in Heildelberg, spectacular operetta - Shubert-Lafayette, September 28, 1925 (Box 2)
- Swan Lake, Music by P. I. Tschaikowsky, choreography after Lev Ivanov - Tulsa Municipal, Tulsa, Oklahoma, October 25, 1963 (Box 2)
- Swan Song by Ben Hecht and Charles MacArthur - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, October 29-November 5, 1947 (Box 2)
- Sweethearts, an operetta in two acts, book by Harry B. Smith and Fred De Gresac, Victor Herbert's production - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, May 30-June 8, 1949 (Box 2)
- The Taming of the Shrew, by William Shakespeare, starring Alfred Lunt and Lynn Fontanne - Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, January 12, 1940 (Box 2)
- The Teahouse of the August Moon by John Patrick, starring John Forsythe and Eli Wallach - Martin Beck Theatre, New York City, April 23, 1955 (Box 2)
- The Tempest by William Shakespeare - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, December 10-20, 1947 (Box 2)
- A Thousand Clowns, starring Van Johnson Gale Gladstone, Doug Chapin, Donald Buka, and Iggie Wolfington - Columbus, Ohio, August 30, 1964 (Box 2)
- Time and The Tide, a new play by Paula and Edward Hussey - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, January 27-February 5, 1949 (Box 2)
- Time Out For Ginger by Ronald Alexander - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, November 22-December 1, 1956 (Box 2)
- Time Remembered, a romantic comedy by Jean Anouilh, starring Helen Hayes, Richard Burton, and Susan Strasberg - Morosco Theatre, New York City, April 28, 1958 (Box 2)
- Helen Traubel, dramatic Soprano, Metropolitan Opera Association, presented by the Community Concert Association - [Nashville] (Box 2)
- Two Blind Mice, a comedy by Sam Spewack - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, October 17-27, 1951 (Box 2)
- The Two Mrs. Carrolls, an exciting mystery thriller by Martin Vale - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, January 21-30, 1954 (Box 2)
- The Unsinkable Molly Brown, a new musical comedy, music and lyrics by Meredith Wilson, Book by Richard Morris - Winter Garden, New York City, June 26, 1961 (Box 2)
- Venus At Large by Henry Denker, starring David Wayne, William Prince, Joyce Jameson and Ernest Truex - Walnut Theatre, Philadelphia (Box 2)
- The Voice of The Turtle by John Van Druten - Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville, October 14-23, 1948 (Box 2)
- Wait a Minim!, a musical entertainment by Leon Gluckman - John Golden Theatre, New York City, April 1966 (Box 2)
- The Women by Clare Booth, December 27 - Ryman Auditorium, Nashville (Box 2)
- Yellow Jack by Sidney Howard in collaboration with Paul DeKruif - Le Petit Theatre, New Orleans, LA, March 25-30, 1935 (Box 2)